# **Brian Mwendwa**

Software Developer

#### Summary

I am a passionate mobile and web developer with 4+ years of experience. I specialize in technologies like React, React Native, Node, SQL, and NoSQL, having worked across diverse industries including Software As A Service, Government, Consultancy and Marketing. My drive stems from a deep passion for leveraging technology to create exceptional user experiences and solve complex challenges. I am excited about contributing my skills and expertise to projects.

#### Experience

Sapient Consulting December 2023 - Present

Software Developer

Nairobi

- Developed a robust mobile app with React Native, optimizing B2C payment processes and improving the user engagement by 20%.
- Built a dynamic festival website using React, seamlessly integrated with a Django (Python) backend, fortifying the client's web infrastructure.
- Developed a crash game betting website using React, expanding the platform's active users to 6000 in the first quarter.
- Documented code and technical specifications, providing a valuable reference for future development and maintenance tasks.
- Collaborated effectively with cross-functional team members, contributing to the design, development, and ongoing support of innovative software applications.

Gratitude India June 2023 - Dec 2023

Frontend Developer Remote

### 

- Collaborated with backend engineers to to build visually appealing interfaces, utilizing Laravel Blade and Figma.
- Redeveloped PHP modules with React, leveraging React's high-speed capabilities to decrease web load times by 6%, leading to overall improvement in system performance.
- Implemented cross-platform UIs for mobile and desktop web applications using React, ensuring a consistent user experience and enhancing accessibility and usability.
- Effectively communicated design concepts to cross-functional teams and upper management, showcasing strong communication skills.

## **Commission on Administrative Justice**

Jan 2022 - August 2023

Software Developer

Nairobi

https://ombudsman.go.ke/

- Developed and deployed a Complaints Management Information System (CMIS), achieving a remarkable 411% increase in usage since its launch in May 2022.
- Collaborated with design teams to craft a user-friendly interface utilizing JavaScript and PHP enhancing the overall user experience of the system.
- Developed the company website, ensuring optimization and adherence to ICT Authority standards. Leveraged Drupal CMS to create a high-quality, efficient web platform that meets SEO requirements.

Jan 2021 - Feb 2022 Gebeya Inc

Software Developer

Remote

https://ms.gebeya.com/

During my tenure at Gebeya Inc, I engaged in several 2-3 month projects with diverse clients, contributing to a match-based system where developers, including myself, were assigned to Gebeya clients for a variety of projects. Throughout these assignments I worked with Ecommerce, Marketing, Advertising and Mobile applications

## Education

2021 University of East London Jan 2024 - Present Africa International University Bachelors Computer Science Masters Information Technology 2nd Class - Upper Division

**Frontend** 

• • • • •

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native, Redux, Figma

Backend

• • • • •

ExpressJs, Firebase, Node, API, REST, SQL, Postgre, MongoDb

**Recent Projects** 

Myglit

June - Aug 2023

**CMIS** 

May 2022 - August 2023

Software As A Service

Myglit is a Software as A Service Platform that is designed to simplify the hiring process for recruiters. The platform automates the Business Process Outsourcing model by offering recruiters and companies a streamlined recruitment processes. This significantly increased job applications, creating a broader talent pool for recruiters.

PHP, NextJs, API, SQL, CI/CD, JavaScript, git, TypeScript, Laravel

Complaints Management Information

System

The Complaints Management Information System to is a system with automated complaint assignments, real-time updates, and detailed reporting features. It is currently used by the office of the Ombudsman Commission on Administrative Justice to overcome challenges with the manual complaints allocation process. The system positively transforms the organization's relationship with Kenyans, enhancing complaint-handling efficiency and customer satisfaction.

PHP, React, JavaScript, SQL, Yii2

Fanaka Bet

Dec 2023- March 2024

Crash game betting website 

Fanaka bet is a fully functional website with real-time features such as chat feeds, betting details, automated betting and a dynamic crash graph. Using React for the frontend and Express for the backend and implementing a robust authentication flow. This led to the transformation of a radio-based betting platform into a highly engaging and comprehensive betting website.

React, Express, API, JWT, MongoDB, Postgre

Furaia Mobile App

Feb - April 2024 iOS and Android App

⊘ Playstore link

Furaia simplifies purchasing in restaurants by enabling users to conveniently make payments through their phones using MPESA and other digital gateways, it streamlines transactions, enhancing user experience and business efficiency. The app's innovative pointbased system allows users to redeem points for rewards or purchases from affiliated businesses. It revolutionizes mobile commerce, solving the challenge of seamless payments and driving customer satisfaction while promoting business growth across various industries.

React Native, Expo, iOS, Android

References

Macharia Kiama

Chief ICT Officer

m.kiama@ombudsman.go.ke

Peter Njeru

Marketing Head CMC motors

peternjeru@gmail.com

Wanja Chabaari

**COO Sapient Consulting** 

w.chabaari@wearesapient.com